<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Stefanni Brasil</title>
    <link>https://www.stefannibrasil.me/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Stefanni Brasil</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 24 Sep 2019 06:54:34 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.stefannibrasil.me/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>About Being Humble</title>
      <link>https://www.stefannibrasil.me/posts/about-being-humble/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Sep 2019 06:54:34 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.stefannibrasil.me/posts/about-being-humble/</guid>
      <description>Today I listened to this Canadian Couch Potato podcast episode. It was a talk with Dr. Steve Wendel on the Investor Success.
The episode, besides the great content, caught my attention when Dr. Wendel mentioned that financial advisors and their clients have different expectations from each other.
They discussed research showing that financial advisors have high expectations that their clients, beyond other goals, were counting on them to avoid making bad investments decisions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About Cognitive Bias and Investments</title>
      <link>https://www.stefannibrasil.me/posts/about-cognitive-bias-and-investments/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Sep 2019 06:50:46 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.stefannibrasil.me/posts/about-cognitive-bias-and-investments/</guid>
      <description>Everyone who is in debt today (and originally didn’t plan to be), once thought they would be able to pay it back in a few years.
 Everyone who (unfortunately) died climbing the everest, once thought they were prepared to reach the peak.
  Not that i’m the first one to think that, but this insight does not come to us naturally. The first book that i read about the way we think was Thinking, fast and slow.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About Me</title>
      <link>https://www.stefannibrasil.me/about-me/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Sep 2019 10:05:22 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.stefannibrasil.me/about-me/</guid>
      <description>Hello, I’m stefanni.
I’m originally from brazil but i’ve been living in Vancouver, BC since 2018.
I’m a software developer working at Lendesk, and currently bootstrapping a side-project called hexdevs with my partner Thiago Araujo. If you are a developer and are interested in working remotely (or how to work remotely more efficiently), finding a job abroad, starting a side business or just getting better as a professional, check us out and let us know what do you think.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Me, New Blog</title>
      <link>https://www.stefannibrasil.me/posts/new-me-new-blog/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Sep 2019 09:59:18 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.stefannibrasil.me/posts/new-me-new-blog/</guid>
      <description>I’ve been thinking of switching my blog to Hugo for a while. The main reason for that is because I’ve changed a lot since I first started writing on my previous wordpress blog. My interests have changed a lot and I think it’s time to move to something new.
I intend to discuss more about different interests, not just about software. That said, you can expect to find here posts about books, financial independence, living a more healthy lifestyle, including adopting environmental-friendly habits, investments, immigrating, and projects that i’m working on as I build them.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>