<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>🌟 Stefanni Brasil</title>
    <link>https://www.stefannibrasil.me/</link>
    <description>Recent content on 🌟 Stefanni Brasil</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 04 Sep 2021 11:03:31 -0700</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.stefannibrasil.me/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Dev With No Experience? Here&#39;s one way to get experience today.</title>
      <link>https://www.stefannibrasil.me/posts/first-ruby-dev-job-no-experience/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Sep 2021 11:03:31 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.stefannibrasil.me/posts/first-ruby-dev-job-no-experience/</guid>
      <description>You&amp;rsquo;re focusing on finding that first Ruby job. You&amp;rsquo;ve been practicing for months or years. You&amp;rsquo;ve been applying to entry-level jobs, even internships.
You polish your resume. Tweak your portfolio. Attach your CV. Press Submit.
Chirp, chirp, chirp 🦗
Nothing happens.
Worse: you do an amazing interview, people loved you. But then they say they are moving forward with someone else that has more experience.
Welp, next time is going to be different.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Unstuck Guide for Self-Taught Developers</title>
      <link>https://www.stefannibrasil.me/posts/unstuck-guide-self-taught-devs/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Aug 2021 22:09:37 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.stefannibrasil.me/posts/unstuck-guide-self-taught-devs/</guid>
      <description>When you get stuck, it&amp;rsquo;s really easy to block yourself from creatively solving your problem.
You start asking why are you so dumb, thinking that you don&amp;rsquo;t have a programming brain or feeling that you&amp;rsquo;ll never understand anything. How is that helpful? It isn&amp;rsquo;t.
The way we talk to each other and ourselves impacts our performance. It&amp;rsquo;s not self-help bullshit. It&amp;rsquo;s how your brain works.
Here&amp;rsquo;s a quick video from one of my favorite neuroscientists, Dr.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Get unstuck on your coding exercise with Just One Exercise</title>
      <link>https://www.stefannibrasil.me/posts/stuck-on-programming-problem/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 31 Jul 2021 12:26:40 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.stefannibrasil.me/posts/stuck-on-programming-problem/</guid>
      <description>You&amp;rsquo;re working on your coding project. Everything is going well.
But it doesn&amp;rsquo;t take too long until you get stuck on your assignment. You try everything you possibly can, with the resources you have.
You are mixing Ruby, JavaScript, Postgres. Doing crash courses, googling. You go to the docs but you don&amp;rsquo;t even know where to look. It&amp;rsquo;s almost as if it&amp;rsquo;s a foreign language.
On StackOverflow, you see the same tips over and over.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Worried you don&#39;t contribute to your team as an early career software engineer?</title>
      <link>https://www.stefannibrasil.me/posts/contribute-team-early-career-software-engineer/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Jul 2021 16:54:11 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.stefannibrasil.me/posts/contribute-team-early-career-software-engineer/</guid>
      <description>You got that first job as an early career software engineer after a long job hunt. You are ready to learn a lot and advance in your career.
Most times you&amp;rsquo;re fine, but sometimes you worry that you don&amp;rsquo;t contribute much value to your team. That you ask stupid questions all the time. Or that you don&amp;rsquo;t have the domain-specific knowledge required to estimate tickets accurately or to handle bugs quickly.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to write Badass READMES for your Github projects</title>
      <link>https://www.stefannibrasil.me/posts/github-readme-examples-and-template/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Jun 2021 20:01:55 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.stefannibrasil.me/posts/github-readme-examples-and-template/</guid>
      <description>You show your GitHub project to people but they don&amp;rsquo;t understand what the code is about. Why should you take time to write a good README if they can simply &amp;ldquo;read the code&amp;rdquo;?
They won&amp;rsquo;t even look at your code if you don&amp;rsquo;t explain what&amp;rsquo;s in it for them. Why should anyone care about it?
What about making them curious about your project? It saves them time, it shows you care about good communication and that by writing good docs you probably write good code as well.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Examples of Successful Self-Taught Developers</title>
      <link>https://www.stefannibrasil.me/posts/examples-successful-self-taught-developers/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Jun 2021 17:08:24 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.stefannibrasil.me/posts/examples-successful-self-taught-developers/</guid>
      <description>Let&amp;rsquo;s say you&amp;rsquo;re learning how to paint. When you look at the famous paintings at the museum, you might start asking yourself:
&amp;ldquo;Will I ever be this good? Is this for me? Will I ever understand all of this?&amp;rdquo;
If these questions sound familiar, it&amp;rsquo;s because you&amp;rsquo;re not alone. It&amp;rsquo;s not just you.
Believe it or not, the same questions can be applied to coding. Some things, like painting and learning how to code, are hard.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On the Job Hunt? Try this one thing to get experience as an early career Ruby dev</title>
      <link>https://www.stefannibrasil.me/posts/tech-job-hunt-with-no-experience/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 May 2021 12:16:52 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.stefannibrasil.me/posts/tech-job-hunt-with-no-experience/</guid>
      <description>&amp;ldquo;Why is it so difficult to find Junior Ruby on Rails dev roles?&amp;quot;
You have finished multiple online courses, workshops and might even read some books to learn Ruby. You start job hunting and you struggle to land a position because of your lack of experience.
So how do you get experience with large Ruby and Rails apps when no one wants to hire early-career devs?
It&amp;rsquo;s a tough market for any early-career dev with little to no experience, so it&amp;rsquo;s no different with Ruby.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rails Conf 2021 Talks for Early Career Devs</title>
      <link>https://www.stefannibrasil.me/posts/rails-conf-2021-talks-early-career-devs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 May 2021 17:27:20 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.stefannibrasil.me/posts/rails-conf-2021-talks-early-career-devs/</guid>
      <description>Now that all Rails Conf 2021 talks, keynotes and workshops are available on YouTube, you might be wondering which ones you should watch first.
If you are just getting started with your Rails or programming journey, here&amp;rsquo;s a list of 6 talks for you (with resources):
1. Implicit to Explicit: Decoding Ruby&amp;rsquo;s Magical Syntax by Justin Gordon [Talk] Do you wish you could understand better what Rails does under the hood?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contribute to Ruby on Rails: filtering &amp; reproducing issues</title>
      <link>https://www.stefannibrasil.me/posts/contribute-to-rails-github-part-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 May 2021 15:08:41 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.stefannibrasil.me/posts/contribute-to-rails-github-part-2/</guid>
      <description>In the last Open Source Thursdays live, Thiago and I shared how we chose a few issues that looked promising for us.
By the end of the post, you&amp;rsquo;ll learn how to filter issues, and how to start contributing to Rails by reproducing a bug.
How to choose your first Ruby on Rails issue Which one from the +300 open issues should you pick? We tried breaking this process down into 2 parts: filtering them by labels, then choosing one that seems easier to fix.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Open Source Thursdays</title>
      <link>https://www.stefannibrasil.me/posts/open-source-thursdays/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 May 2021 12:27:31 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.stefannibrasil.me/posts/open-source-thursdays/</guid>
      <description>What is Open Source Thursdays? Open Source Thursdays is a new project from the hexdevs team, aka me and Thiago.
We started this project because we&amp;rsquo;ve always wanted to contribute to rails! So we thought, why not do it live so more people can join us? Our goal is to make open source contributions more popular.
Neither of us has done this before. The plan is to get there and do everything live, no preparing in advance.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Should I Get an Internship or Keep Practicing my Coding Skills?</title>
      <link>https://www.stefannibrasil.me/posts/should-i-get-an-internship-or-keep-practicing/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 May 2021 11:06:37 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.stefannibrasil.me/posts/should-i-get-an-internship-or-keep-practicing/</guid>
      <description>If you&amp;rsquo;re someone who decided to change careers to work as a web developer, then you might be having a hard time trying to land your first job. You aren&amp;rsquo;t alone.
We all have heard that there are tons of tech jobs in the market but there aren&amp;rsquo;t qualified professionals to fulfill them. So you go and spend days doing online courses and getting certifications so you can join the wave.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Contribute to Ruby on Rails Open Source project</title>
      <link>https://www.stefannibrasil.me/posts/how-to-contribute-to-ruby-on-rails-project-on-github/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Apr 2021 15:43:57 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.stefannibrasil.me/posts/how-to-contribute-to-ruby-on-rails-project-on-github/</guid>
      <description>Step 1: Decide to find one open-source project to contribute 😎
Step 2: Keep looking 👀
Step 3: They are all intimidating, is that normal? 😑
Step 4: What if I contributed to a project I have lots of experience with, like rails? I&amp;rsquo;d love to understand more about this tool I use every day 🤔
Step 5: OMG, the code is huge and scary, Will this even run on my machine?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Will I Find Work if I Learn Ruby in 2021</title>
      <link>https://www.stefannibrasil.me/posts/will-i-find-work-if-i-learn-ruby/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Apr 2021 11:12:56 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.stefannibrasil.me/posts/will-i-find-work-if-i-learn-ruby/</guid>
      <description>Ruby is keeping you interested in transitioning to the software development world. But you&amp;rsquo;re not sure you&amp;rsquo;re gonna be employable. You might have heard that you should just choose JavaScript because, you know, everyone is saying Ruby is a dying domain.
But you don&amp;rsquo;t see yourself keeping up with the Kardashians traditional JS web dev world.
You&amp;rsquo;ve heard that there are plenty of Ruby/Rails jobs out there. But how do you get your first one as an early career dev?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Check your email</title>
      <link>https://www.stefannibrasil.me/confirm-your-subscription/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Apr 2021 17:07:09 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.stefannibrasil.me/confirm-your-subscription/</guid>
      <description>Welcome! Please check your inbox to confirm your subscription: The email is coming from &amp;ldquo;Stefanni&amp;rdquo;. If you can&amp;rsquo;t find it in your inbox, check your other tabs or the spam folder.
Still can&amp;rsquo;t find it? Send a message to hi@stefannibrasil.me and I&amp;rsquo;ll fix it for you.
See you in your inbox!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rails Conf 2021 Slides &#43; Rails API-only Cheat Sheet</title>
      <link>https://www.stefannibrasil.me/railsconf/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Apr 2021 19:00:24 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.stefannibrasil.me/railsconf/</guid>
      <description>Hi, nice seeing you here! Here&amp;rsquo;s what you&amp;rsquo;re looking for:
Slides
-- Rails API-only Cheat Sheet
Thank you for checking these materials out! Let me know your thoughts, feedback or suggestions! :)
-Stefanni Brasil
 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Should you create a new Rails app as API-only?</title>
      <link>https://www.stefannibrasil.me/posts/should-you-go-with-rails-api-only/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Apr 2021 17:41:48 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.stefannibrasil.me/posts/should-you-go-with-rails-api-only/</guid>
      <description>Before you get too excited and run rails new thecoolest --api on your terminal, it might be a good idea to take some time to consider what your needs are.
How different is a Rails API-only from a full-stack Rails app? As you can see in the image below, the API-only is a lighter version of a full stack Rails app:
The reason why it&amp;rsquo;s lighter is because Rails API-only won&amp;rsquo;t render HTML pages, handle user sessions &amp;amp; cookies, nor display any assets.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thank You</title>
      <link>https://www.stefannibrasil.me/thank-you/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Apr 2021 18:17:12 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.stefannibrasil.me/thank-you/</guid>
      <description>You’re on the list!
I send out a new letter almost every week. It’ll come from hi@stefannibrasil.me
If you haven’t yet, you can check out the past blog posts or follow me on Twitter for more thoughts on coding, career and happiness.
Welcome to this newsletter! It&amp;rsquo;s great to have you here ☕
-Stefanni</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>5 Ways to Handle Your Rails API Authentication</title>
      <link>https://www.stefannibrasil.me/posts/5-ways-to-handle-your-rails-api-authentication/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Apr 2021 13:12:38 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.stefannibrasil.me/posts/5-ways-to-handle-your-rails-api-authentication/</guid>
      <description>Which authentication strategy should you use for Rails API? How to implement a secure authentication strategy is by the far the most confusing part of building an API.
It&amp;rsquo;s important to evaluate your app requirements before choosing any strategy in the first place to avoid any security implications.
To help you figure out which authentication strategy is the best for your case, here are 5 possible solutions for you:
Rails API-only If your API is running as a standalone app and you don&amp;rsquo;t need a web interface of any sort, then a header-based token auth might be enough.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Balancing present and future with the FIRE movement</title>
      <link>https://www.stefannibrasil.me/posts/balance-present-future-fire/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Mar 2021 13:19:46 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.stefannibrasil.me/posts/balance-present-future-fire/</guid>
      <description>The first time I realized I was being too future-focused was when I got in a bad mental health state in 2020.
I didn’t want to pay for Cognitive-Behavior Therapy sessions. I could have, but I didn’t want to spend money on it. Not super clever, I know.
Looking back, I get mad at myself for putting savings before my mental health needs. This experience changed me, since it took me less than one year to improve my mental health, live a happier and confident life.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Is Ruby on Rails Still Relevant in 2021?</title>
      <link>https://www.stefannibrasil.me/posts/is-ruby-on-rails-still-relevant/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Feb 2021 10:52:41 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.stefannibrasil.me/posts/is-ruby-on-rails-still-relevant/</guid>
      <description>&amp;ldquo;Maybe Python or Go is a better choice? Or even Javascript?&amp;rdquo; If you&amp;rsquo;ve been asking yourself these questions, this post is for you.
When I was learning how to code in 2016, Ruby on Rails was trending and every startup was using it. It was obvious that learning Rails would be an easy way to get my first dev job. We&amp;rsquo;re in 2021, though, and things have changed.
The answer to &amp;ldquo;Is Rails still relevant?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hi there! 👋</title>
      <link>https://www.stefannibrasil.me/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Jan 2021 10:45:09 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.stefannibrasil.me/about/</guid>
      <description>About Stefanni Brasil - The Kind Developer</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>8 exercises to build confidence in yourself</title>
      <link>https://www.stefannibrasil.me/posts/how-to-practice-self-confidence/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Jan 2021 10:36:51 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.stefannibrasil.me/posts/how-to-practice-self-confidence/</guid>
      <description>I believed I had to be born confident, and I wasn’t, so why keep trying? How happy I am to have been wrong about that!
This post offers exercises from the book “The Confidence Code: The Science and Art of Self-Assurance - What Women Should Know” and from Cognitive Behaviour Therapy.
Start practicing these 8 key activities and see how you feel a few weeks from now.
Ready? 🚀
Exercises to build self-confidence  When in doubt, ACT.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
