<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Stefanni Brasil</title>
    <link>https://www.stefannibrasil.me/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Stefanni Brasil</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 20 Apr 2021 11:12:56 -0700</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.stefannibrasil.me/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Will I Find Work if I Learn Ruby?</title>
      <link>https://www.stefannibrasil.me/posts/will-i-find-work-if-i-learn-ruby/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Apr 2021 11:12:56 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.stefannibrasil.me/posts/will-i-find-work-if-i-learn-ruby/</guid>
      <description>Ruby is keeping you interested in transitioning to the software development world. But you&amp;rsquo;re not sure you&amp;rsquo;re gonna be employable. You might have heard that you should just choose JavaScript because, you know, Ruby is a dying domain.
But you don&amp;rsquo;t see yourself keeping up with the Kardashians traditional JS web dev world.
You know there are plenty of Ruby/Rails jobs out there. But how do you get your first one?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Check your email</title>
      <link>https://www.stefannibrasil.me/confirm-your-subscription/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Apr 2021 17:07:09 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.stefannibrasil.me/confirm-your-subscription/</guid>
      <description>Check your email! Be sure to check your inbox to confirm your subscription:
The email is coming from &amp;ldquo;Stefanni&amp;rdquo;. If you can&amp;rsquo;t find it in your inbox, check your other tabs or the spam folder.
Still can&amp;rsquo;t find it? Send me an email at stefanni at hexdevs dot com and I&amp;rsquo;ll fix it for you.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rails Conf 2021 Slides &#43; Rails API-only Cheat Sheet</title>
      <link>https://www.stefannibrasil.me/railsconf/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Apr 2021 19:00:24 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.stefannibrasil.me/railsconf/</guid>
      <description>Hi, nice seeing you here! Here&amp;rsquo;s what you&amp;rsquo;re looking for:
Slides
Rails API-only Cheat Sheet
If you&amp;rsquo;d like to get more cheat sheets, code snippets, all Ruby on Rails things, you can sign up for my mailing list here:
 Thank you for checking these materials out! Let me know your thoughts, feedback or suggestions! :)
-Stefanni Brasil</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Should you create a new Rails app as API-only?</title>
      <link>https://www.stefannibrasil.me/posts/should-you-go-with-rails-api-only/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Apr 2021 17:41:48 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.stefannibrasil.me/posts/should-you-go-with-rails-api-only/</guid>
      <description>Before you get too excited and run rails new thecoolest --api on your terminal, you need to take some time to consider what your needs are.
How to choose which Rails alternative to implement your API? To help you decide which Rails alternative you should use, here is a comparison of the most common API scenarios:
   Requirements Rails API-only Full Rails stack     Login/logout (sessions) N Y   Cookies N Y   Social logins (FB, Google) N Y   Render HTML (web interfaces) N Y   HTTP Header Authentication Y Y   JSON Y Y    If your client will be a SPA (single-page application) or a native mobile app, and that&amp;rsquo;s where all the user interaction is going to live, then Rails API-only is a good choice.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thank You</title>
      <link>https://www.stefannibrasil.me/thank-you/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Apr 2021 18:17:12 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.stefannibrasil.me/thank-you/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to this newsletter!
See you in your inbox!
-Stefanni</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>5 Ways to Handle Your Rails API Authentication</title>
      <link>https://www.stefannibrasil.me/posts/5-ways-to-handle-your-rails-api-authentication/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Apr 2021 13:12:38 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.stefannibrasil.me/posts/5-ways-to-handle-your-rails-api-authentication/</guid>
      <description>Which authentication strategy should you use for Rails API? How to implement a secure authentication strategy is by the far the most confusing part of building an API.
It&amp;rsquo;s important to evaluate your app requirements before choosing any strategy in the first place to avoid any security implications.
To help you figure out which authentication strategy is the best for your case, here are 5 possible solutions for you:
Rails API-only If your API is running as a standalone app and you don&amp;rsquo;t need a web interface of any sort, then a header-based token auth might be enough.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Balancing present and future with the FIRE movement</title>
      <link>https://www.stefannibrasil.me/posts/balance-present-future-fire/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Mar 2021 13:19:46 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.stefannibrasil.me/posts/balance-present-future-fire/</guid>
      <description>The first time I realized I was being too future-focused was when I got in a bad mental health state in 2020.
I didn’t want to pay for Cognitive-Behavior Therapy sessions. I could have, but I didn’t want to spend money on it. Not super clever, I know.
Looking back, I get mad at myself for putting savings before my mental health needs. This experience changed me, since it took me less than one year to improve my mental health, live a happier and confident life.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Is Ruby on Rails Still Relevant in 2021?</title>
      <link>https://www.stefannibrasil.me/posts/is-ruby-on-rails-still-relevant/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Feb 2021 10:52:41 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.stefannibrasil.me/posts/is-ruby-on-rails-still-relevant/</guid>
      <description>&amp;ldquo;Maybe Python or Go is a better choice? Or even Javascript?&amp;rdquo; If you&amp;rsquo;ve been asking yourself these questions, this post is for you.
When I was learning how to code in 2016, Ruby on Rails was trending and every startup was using it. It was obvious that learning Rails would be an easy way to get my first dev job. We&amp;rsquo;re in 2021, though, and things have changed.
The answer to &amp;ldquo;Is Rails still relevant?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hi there! 👋</title>
      <link>https://www.stefannibrasil.me/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Jan 2021 10:45:09 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.stefannibrasil.me/about/</guid>
      <description>About Stefanni Brasil - The Kind Developer</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>8 activites to build self-confidence</title>
      <link>https://www.stefannibrasil.me/posts/how-to-practice-self-confidence/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Jan 2021 10:36:51 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.stefannibrasil.me/posts/how-to-practice-self-confidence/</guid>
      <description>I believed I had to had born confident. And I wasn’t, so why keep trying? How happy I am to have been wrong about that!
This post brings some exercises from the book “The Confidence Code: The Science and Art of Self-Assurance - What women should know”, and some lessons from my Cognitive Behaviour Therapy sessions.
Start practicing these 8 keys activities and see how you feel a few weeks from now.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
