<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>mental health on 🚴‍♀️ Stefanni Brasil</title>
    <link>https://www.stefannibrasil.me/tags/mental-health/</link>
    <description>Recent content in mental health on 🚴‍♀️ Stefanni Brasil</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 16 Jun 2022 17:15:55 -0700</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.stefannibrasil.me/tags/mental-health/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>My Experience With Anxiety, Depression, Therapy and Taking Anti-Depressants</title>
      <link>https://www.stefannibrasil.me/posts/my-experience-with-anti-depressants/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jun 2022 17:15:55 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.stefannibrasil.me/posts/my-experience-with-anti-depressants/</guid>
      <description>When I decided to start Cognitive-Behavior Therapy (CBT), I embarked on a quest: I wanted to find out why my brain was my enemy.
I didn&amp;rsquo;t get it. If my brain&amp;rsquo;s goal was to keep me alive, why was I wanting to not be alive anymore? It didn&amp;rsquo;t make sense.
I wanted to find out what was wrong with my brain.
After years of therapy, meditation, and neuroscience research, I got to the conclusion that there was nothing wrong with me.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why you don&#39;t need to feel confident to be successful</title>
      <link>https://www.stefannibrasil.me/posts/notes/attention-performance-peter-haberl/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jun 2022 19:32:56 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.stefannibrasil.me/posts/notes/attention-performance-peter-haberl/</guid>
      <description>Nothing kills confidence more than waiting to feel confident to do something.
You will be waiting forever. Attention and Determination is what you need to achieve your goals &amp;ndash; no matter how scary they are.
Learning about the power of Attention and Determination made me fall in love with this series about achievement orientation from the First Person Plural podcast. It&amp;rsquo;s one of my favorite podcasts (after hexdevs, of course ;).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Imposter Syndrome? You&#39;re doing better than you think.</title>
      <link>https://www.stefannibrasil.me/posts/notes/imposter-syndrome/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Jan 2022 19:12:08 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.stefannibrasil.me/posts/notes/imposter-syndrome/</guid>
      <description>Hi, welcome! The posts under &amp;ldquo;/notes&amp;rdquo; are just that: notes about things I&amp;rsquo;ve read or watched. I used to just write them for myself. I figured sharing them is more helpful than keeping them just to myself. Enjoy!
 Sharing a few notes about Imposter Syndrome based on the work of Dr. Vanessa Bohns and Dr. Randy Patterson.
The Science of Influence   I finished watching this interview with Dr.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>8 exercises to build confidence in yourself</title>
      <link>https://www.stefannibrasil.me/posts/how-to-practice-self-confidence/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Jan 2021 10:36:51 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.stefannibrasil.me/posts/how-to-practice-self-confidence/</guid>
      <description>I believed I had to be born confident, and I wasn’t, so why keep trying? How happy I am to have been wrong about that!
This post offers exercises from the book “The Confidence Code: The Science and Art of Self-Assurance - What Women Should Know” and from Cognitive Behaviour Therapy.
Start practicing these 8 key activities and see how you feel a few weeks from now.
Ready? 🚀
Exercises to build self-confidence  When in doubt, ACT.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
