<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>early career devs on 🌟 Stefanni Brasil</title>
    <link>https://www.stefannibrasil.me/tags/early-career-devs/</link>
    <description>Recent content in early career devs on 🌟 Stefanni Brasil</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 23 Jun 2021 20:01:55 -0700</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.stefannibrasil.me/tags/early-career-devs/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>How to write Badass Github READMES for your projects</title>
      <link>https://www.stefannibrasil.me/posts/github-readme-examples-and-template/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Jun 2021 20:01:55 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.stefannibrasil.me/posts/github-readme-examples-and-template/</guid>
      <description>You show your project on your GitHub portfolio to people but they don&amp;rsquo;t understand it. It&amp;rsquo;s easy to think they can simply &amp;ldquo;read the code&amp;rdquo;. You&amp;rsquo;re adding more friction to their job. Nobody likes that.
What about making them feel impressed by improving your README? It saves time, it shows you care about working in a team and that by writing good docs you probably write good code as well.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Examples of Successful Self-Taught Developers</title>
      <link>https://www.stefannibrasil.me/posts/examples-successful-self-taught-developers/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Jun 2021 17:08:24 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.stefannibrasil.me/posts/examples-successful-self-taught-developers/</guid>
      <description>Let&amp;rsquo;s say you&amp;rsquo;re learning how to paint. When you look at the famous paintings at the museum, you might start asking yourself:
&amp;ldquo;Will I ever be this good? Is this for me? Will I ever understand all of this?&amp;rdquo;
If these questions sound familiar, it&amp;rsquo;s because you&amp;rsquo;re not alone. It&amp;rsquo;s not just you.
Believe it or not, the same questions can be applied to coding. Some things, like painting and learning how to code, are hard.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On the Job Hunt? Try this one thing to get experience as an early career Ruby dev</title>
      <link>https://www.stefannibrasil.me/posts/tech-job-hunt-with-no-experience/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 May 2021 12:16:52 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.stefannibrasil.me/posts/tech-job-hunt-with-no-experience/</guid>
      <description>&amp;ldquo;Why is it so difficult to find Junior Ruby on Rails dev roles?&amp;quot;
You have finished multiple online courses, workshops and might even read some books to learn Ruby. You start job hunting and you struggle to land a position because of your lack of experience.
So how do you get experience with large Ruby and Rails apps when no one wants to hire early-career devs?
It&amp;rsquo;s a tough market for any early-career dev with little to no experience, so it&amp;rsquo;s no different with Ruby.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Should I Get an Internship or Keep Practicing my Coding Skills?</title>
      <link>https://www.stefannibrasil.me/posts/should-i-get-an-internship-or-keep-practicing/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 May 2021 11:06:37 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.stefannibrasil.me/posts/should-i-get-an-internship-or-keep-practicing/</guid>
      <description>If you&amp;rsquo;re someone who decided to change careers to work as a web developer, then you might be having a hard time trying to land your first job. You aren&amp;rsquo;t alone.
We all have heard that there are tons of tech jobs in the market but there aren&amp;rsquo;t qualified professionals to fulfill them. So you go and spend days doing online courses and getting certifications so you can join the wave.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
