<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>books on 🌟 Stefanni Brasil</title>
    <link>https://www.stefannibrasil.me/tags/books/</link>
    <description>Recent content in books on 🌟 Stefanni Brasil</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 09 May 2022 16:03:42 -0700</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.stefannibrasil.me/tags/books/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The 3 Things That Improved My Online Writing Process By Reading &#39;The Art And Business Of Online Writing&#39;</title>
      <link>https://www.stefannibrasil.me/posts/notes/the-art-and-business-of-online-writing/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 May 2022 16:03:42 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.stefannibrasil.me/posts/notes/the-art-and-business-of-online-writing/</guid>
      <description>Writing is easy. Anyone can write a post of 500 words.
Right?
But what does it take to go from a writer to becoming a writer with readers? Insights gathered by trying different things, willingness to make mistakes, and working in public.
Therefore, I always get curious when I find people who have successfully created writing careers, or businesses on top of their writing skills. This curiosity led me to read &amp;ldquo;The Art and Business of Online Writing&amp;rdquo;, by Nicolas Cole.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The One quote from &#39;Work Clean&#39; to deliver excellence as a Creator</title>
      <link>https://www.stefannibrasil.me/posts/notes/work-clean-mise-en-place/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Mar 2022 20:38:01 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.stefannibrasil.me/posts/notes/work-clean-mise-en-place/</guid>
      <description>What differentiates perfectionism from excellence? I only learned the difference recently.
Reading this quote from the book &amp;ldquo;Work Clean: The life-changing power of mise-en-place to organize your life, work, and mind&amp;rdquo;, changed how I approached my work.
I used to feel proud by saying I was a perfectionist. That meant months, years of planning every single detail of everything. Setting the stakes higher as time went by.
Perfectionism is a great excuse for trying to control the results.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
