<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>online writing on 🚴‍♀️ Stefanni Brasil</title>
    <link>https://www.stefannibrasil.me/tags/online-writing/</link>
    <description>Recent content in online writing on 🚴‍♀️ Stefanni Brasil</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 17 Oct 2025 08:03:42 -0700</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.stefannibrasil.me/tags/online-writing/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Darkness enter the timeless room</title>
      <link>https://www.stefannibrasil.me/posts/notes/where-there-is-no-time/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Oct 2025 08:03:42 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.stefannibrasil.me/posts/notes/where-there-is-no-time/</guid>
      <description> Meters and meters away from home  I find myself where there’s no time   I opened the window for fresh air  As I am in complete darkness   That’s when Darkness itself entered the room  An ancient caregiver of the land and time  It just stands there, occupying its space  Indistinguishable from its friend, the night   When you seek darkness  it&#39;s because you&#39;ve trapped your light inside   And there it lies, waiting for you to wake up  Blind, looking for the outside morning light that never comes </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Coffee-free Journey: Mastering Chicory Root Coffee</title>
      <link>https://www.stefannibrasil.me/posts/notes/cafeine-free-chicory-root-tea/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Oct 2025 06:03:42 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.stefannibrasil.me/posts/notes/cafeine-free-chicory-root-tea/</guid>
      <description>More than one year ago, I decided that coffee (caffeine in general) wasn&amp;rsquo;t making me any good. I felt hostage to coffee: if I didn&amp;rsquo;t drink it every morning, I&amp;rsquo;d get a terrible headache, forcing me to drink it to avoid being in pain. It also made me feel more anxious during the day. Why was I doing this to myself?
When I had to leave early and didn&amp;rsquo;t have time for drinking coffee, I would seek out for coffee right away.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2024: reflections on the moral obligations of being a better person</title>
      <link>https://www.stefannibrasil.me/posts/notes/2024-reflections/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Nov 2024 19:23:29 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.stefannibrasil.me/posts/notes/2024-reflections/</guid>
      <description>Last year when visiting my local library (something that I love to do), an intriguing book cover caught my attention. It had a bright yellow cover with an interesting title: How to Be Perfect: The Correct Moral Answer to Every Question, from Michael Schur.
I checked it out without any questioning. It explains the process Michael went through to produce one of my favorite TV shows: &amp;ldquo;The Good Place&amp;rdquo;. If you have ever watched shows produced by Michael Schur, you might antecipate that the book is funny.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sometimes, I want to be a tree</title>
      <link>https://www.stefannibrasil.me/posts/notes/fall-thoughts/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Mar 2024 19:12:08 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.stefannibrasil.me/posts/notes/fall-thoughts/</guid>
      <description>The wind, with no excuses and surprises, takes over all the leaves from the trees.
One day, I was walking somewhere and witnessed the wind taking the remaining leaves of a tree. All I could think of was:
&amp;ldquo;wouldn&amp;rsquo;t be great if I could let things go just like that? A strong wind meets my past, removes all that doesn&amp;rsquo;t serve me anymore. For some time, I don&amp;rsquo;t carry anything, just nurture the roots of my core self to give space for a new season&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The 3 Things That Improved My Online Writing Process After Reading &#39;The Art And Business Of Online Writing&#39;</title>
      <link>https://www.stefannibrasil.me/posts/notes/the-art-and-business-of-online-writing/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 May 2022 16:03:42 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.stefannibrasil.me/posts/notes/the-art-and-business-of-online-writing/</guid>
      <description>Writing is easy. Anyone can write a post of 500 words.
But what does it take to go from a writer to becoming a writer with readers? Insights gathered by trying different things, willingness to make mistakes, and working in public.
Therefore, I always get curious when I find people who have successfully created writing careers, or businesses on top of their writing skills. This curiosity led me to read &amp;ldquo;The Art and Business of Online Writing&amp;rdquo;, by Nicolas Cole (my co-founder, Thiago Araujo, also recommended reading it).</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
