<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>online writing on 🌟 Stefanni Brasil</title>
    <link>https://www.stefannibrasil.me/tags/online-writing/</link>
    <description>Recent content in online writing on 🌟 Stefanni Brasil</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 12 Nov 2024 19:23:29 -0700</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.stefannibrasil.me/tags/online-writing/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>2024: reflections on the moral obligations of being a better person</title>
      <link>https://www.stefannibrasil.me/posts/notes/2024-reflections/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Nov 2024 19:23:29 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.stefannibrasil.me/posts/notes/2024-reflections/</guid>
      <description>Last year when visiting my local library (something that I love to do), an intriguing book cover caught my attention. It had a bright yellow cover with an interesting title: How to Be Perfect: The Correct Moral Answer to Every Question, from Michael Schur.
I checked it out without any questioning. It explains the process Michael went through to produce one of my favorite TV shows: &amp;ldquo;The Good Place&amp;rdquo;. If you have ever watched shows produced by Michael Schur, you might antecipate that the book is funny.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sometimes, I want to be a tree</title>
      <link>https://www.stefannibrasil.me/posts/notes/fall-thoughts/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Mar 2024 19:12:08 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.stefannibrasil.me/posts/notes/fall-thoughts/</guid>
      <description>The wind, with no excuses and surprises, takes over all the leaves from the trees.
One day, I was walking somewhere and witnessed the wind taking the remaining leaves of a tree. All I could think of was:
&amp;ldquo;wouldn&amp;rsquo;t be great if I could let things go just like that? A strong wind meets my past, removes all that doesn&amp;rsquo;t serve me anymore. For some time, I don&amp;rsquo;t carry anything, just nurture the roots of my core self to give space for a new season&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The 3 Things That Improved My Online Writing Process After Reading &#39;The Art And Business Of Online Writing&#39;</title>
      <link>https://www.stefannibrasil.me/posts/notes/the-art-and-business-of-online-writing/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 May 2022 16:03:42 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.stefannibrasil.me/posts/notes/the-art-and-business-of-online-writing/</guid>
      <description>Writing is easy. Anyone can write a post of 500 words.
But what does it take to go from a writer to becoming a writer with readers? Insights gathered by trying different things, willingness to make mistakes, and working in public.
Therefore, I always get curious when I find people who have successfully created writing careers, or businesses on top of their writing skills. This curiosity led me to read &amp;ldquo;The Art and Business of Online Writing&amp;rdquo;, by Nicolas Cole (my co-founder, Thiago Araujo, also recommended reading it).</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
